{
    "id": "3d25c82158bf445986fe3522eed09ce6",
    "title": "Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I did it because I wanted to.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of reason is usually introduced by a conjunction like as, since or because.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "As he was not there, I spoke to his mother.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of reason is usually introduced by a conjunction like as, since or because.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Just as he entered the room, the clock struck eleven.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of time shows the time of the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you eat too much you will fall ill.",
            "description": "Adverb clauses of condition are usually introduced by the subordinating conjunctions if or unless.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We asked him many questions when he returned.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of time shows the time of the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My parents were poor though they were of noble birth.",
            "description": "Adverb clauses of concession or contrast are usually introduced by the conjunctions though and although.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Mary had a little lamb whose fleece was as white as snow.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘whose fleece was as white as snow’ modifies the noun lamb.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I still live in the same city where I was born.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause 'where I was born' modifies the noun city.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He met a girl whose eyes were blue.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause whose eyes were blue modifies the noun girl.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I often wonder how you are getting on.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘how you are getting on’ acts as the object of the verb wonder. ",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me where I lived.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘where I lived’ acts as the object of the verb asked. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The fact that he is silent proves his guilt.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause 'the fact that he is silent' is the object of the verb proves. ",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}